<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Opinion on Likelyblue</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/opinion/</link>
    <description>Recent content from Likelyblue</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    <managingEditor>tahoso@likely.blue (Tahoso)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>tahoso@likely.blue (Tahoso)</webMaster>
    
    <copyright>All articles on this blog are licensed under the BY-NC-SA license agreement unless otherwise stated. Please indicate the source when reprinting!</copyright>
    
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 19:19:41 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
    
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss&#43;xml" />
    

    
    

    <item>
      <title>Antidote, Adobe s&#39;ils créent un correcteur d&#39;orthographe</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/antidote-adobe-ils-cr%C3%A9ent-un-correcteur-orthographe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2025 19:19:41 -0400</pubDate>
      <author>tahoso@likely.blue (Tahoso)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/antidote-adobe-ils-cr%C3%A9ent-un-correcteur-orthographe/</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h1>Antidote, Adobe s'ils créent un correcteur d'orthographe</h1><p>Author: Tahoso(tahoso@likely.blue)</p>
        
          <p>Je viens de recevoir un grand faveur de mon CÉGEP en me donnant une licence d&rsquo;Antidote gratuitement. «Cependant, je suis sur Linux, alors ça ne va pas fonctionner», pense je. Heureusement, il me semble qu&rsquo;il y a aussi une version web. Je suis en train d&rsquo;être content, car je viens de gagner un correcteur d&rsquo;orthographe qui normalement coûte 89,00 CAD, gratuitement.</p>
<p>Tout mon bonheur se termine quand je réalise que, f*ck, la licence qui coûte 89 dollars n&rsquo;offre aucune compatibilité pour Linux. <strong>OUI, AUCUNE compatibilité pour Linux</strong>. Si c&rsquo;était moi qui payais pour ce correcteur, je ne serais pas ici maintenant; je serais plutôt au siège de Druide. Je dois payer 24 CAD pour accéder à la version web pour 1 an. Ce n&rsquo;est pas beaucoup d&rsquo;argent, honnêtement. MAIS C&rsquo;EST QUAND MÊME 89 CAD, qui était déjà payé par mon CÉGEP.</p>
        
        <hr><p>Published on 2025-09-08 at <a href='http://localhost:1313/'>Likelyblue</a>, last modified on 2025-09-08</p>]]>
      </description>
      
        <category>Opinion</category>
      
    </item>
    
    

    <item>
      <title>AdGuard Home vs Pi-hole: Why did I choose AdGuard?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/adguard-home-vs-pi-hole/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Jul 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      <author>tahoso@likely.blue (Tahoso)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/adguard-home-vs-pi-hole/</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h1>AdGuard Home vs Pi-hole: Why did I choose AdGuard?</h1><p>Author: Tahoso(tahoso@likely.blue)</p>
        
          <h1 id="my-story">
<a class="header-anchor" href="#my-story"></a>
My Story
</h1><p>Back when I started my home lab journey, I began with Pi-hole. Many mainstream YouTubers recommended it, like LTT (Linus Tech Tips) and SOG (SomeOrdinaryGamers). It was amazing as my second self-hosted project, after I set up Nextcloud. However, it broke after I updated the Ubuntu system it was running on.</p>
<p>After that first time, I started to learn more about Docker and web-native stuff.That is why I switched to using Pi-hole in Docker. I felt confident that it wouldn&rsquo;t randomly break because of an update again. Unfortunately, I was wrong. It broke again a few months after the second Pi-hole setup.</p>
        
        <hr><p>Published on 2025-07-28 at <a href='http://localhost:1313/'>Likelyblue</a>, last modified on 2025-07-28</p>]]>
      </description>
      
        <category>Opinion</category>
      
    </item>
    
    

    <item>
      <title>My Experience With Antivirus on Linux</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/post/my-experience-with-antivirus-on-linux/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 00:00:00 &#43;0000</pubDate>
      <author>tahoso@likely.blue (Tahoso)</author>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/post/my-experience-with-antivirus-on-linux/</guid>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h1>My Experience With Antivirus on Linux</h1><p>Author: Tahoso(tahoso@likely.blue)</p>
        
          <p>So I installed Anti-Virus software on my Linux system, and the reason behind it is pretty simple: I was bored. Yea! In my opinion, there is no better reason than that. I wanted to have fun tinkering with something, and AV seemed like a good idea at the time. I don&rsquo;t think everyone on Linux needs to have AV, and in fact, I believe it&rsquo;s quite useless on Linux for now. If you&rsquo;re interested in learning more about the subject(AV), you can visit <a href="https://easylinuxtipsproject.blogspot.com/p/security.html#ID1.1">this blog</a>. For me, this was just for testing and learning purposes.</p>
        
        <hr><p>Published on 2025-06-18 at <a href='http://localhost:1313/'>Likelyblue</a>, last modified on 2025-07-12</p>]]>
      </description>
      
        <category>Opinion</category>
      
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
